Otto Klemperer Archive
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1915-1971 (Box 1-43, 103-106, 108)
  - Works by Otto Klemperer (Box 1-37, 103-106, 108)
    - [Lieder]
      - Mag sie sich immer ergänzen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 22.8.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Meine Mutter, die Hur', Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/24)
      - Meine Mutter, die Hur', Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/24)
      - Mit der Teutschen Freundschaft, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 16.6.69 Zürich. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/25)
      - Nachtgesang, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 7.9.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/26)
      - Nur wer die Sehnsucht kennt see [Lieder] Drei Mignon Lieder
      - O du, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies); At end: 20 - VI - 1958 Jerusalem. Also at end: untranslated Hebrew text. (Box-folder 9/27)
      - O du, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (2 copies) (Box-folder 9/27)
      - Psalm 23 see also Psalm 23 [non-Lieder], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/28)
      - Psalm 23 see also Psalm 23 [non-Lieder], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations; On t.p.: For Helmuth and Marianne. 3.5.59 Amsterdam. (Box-folder 9/28)
      - Ein rascher Sinn, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 21.5.68 Wien. (Box-folder 9/29)
      - Ein rascher Sinn, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 23.5.68 Wien. (Box-folder 9/29)
      - Ein rascher Sinn, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; Also on t.p.: An meine Frau. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/29)
      - Rezensent, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 6.1.68. (Box-folder 9/30)
      - Rezensent, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/30)
      - Schlafe, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein see [Lieder] Schlaflied
      - Schlafen, schlafen, nichts als schlafen, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Schlaflied [Schlaf, mein Kind!], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Schlaflied [Schlaf, mein Kind!], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Schlaflied [Schlafe, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein] see also [Lieder] Wiegenlied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Schlaflied [Schlafe, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein]] see also [Lieder] Wiegenlied, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Schlafe, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein. Also on p. 1: Wiegenlied. (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Sie haben wegen der Trunkenheit, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Westöstlicher Divan. At end: 21.6.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Sie liebten sich beide, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Sie liebten sich beide, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score (2 copies) (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Sitz ich allein, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 2.5.71 Zürich. (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Sitz ich allein, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Sitz ich allein, Copyist's manuscript of part for solo violin (Box-folder 10/6)
      - 'Sliegt eine Stadt see [Lieder] Dehmel
      - So ist die Lieb', Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Soldatenlied zu Wallensteins Lager, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 26.8.68 Edinburgh. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/8)
      - Ein Stündlein wohl vor Tag, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Ein Stündlein wohl vor Tag, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies) (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Ein Stündlein wohl vor Tag, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (2 copies) (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Suleika, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Hochbeglückt in deiner Liebe. Also on t.p.: Westöstlicher Divan. At end: 21.6.68. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/10)
      - Suleika aus dem Westöstlicher Divan, Printed piano-vocal score with markings (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Suleika aus dem Westöstlicher Divan, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score with markings (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Tadelt man, dass wir uns lieben, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 20.5.68. (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Tadelt man, dass wir uns lieben, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Der Tod, das ist die kühle Nacht, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 26.11.67 Zürich. (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Der Tod, das ist die kühle Nacht, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Tristan, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 25.4.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/14)
      - Trost in Tränen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 20.9.68 London. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/15)
      - Die überflüssige Vorsicht, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Ungeduld, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 12.5.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Ungeduld, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 24.8.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Ungesucht gefunden see [Lieder] Lied
      - Unter Freuden, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 22.1.68. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/18)
      - Das verlassene Mägdlein, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 5.4.58 Zürich. (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Das verlassene Mägdlein, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies) (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Das verlassene Mägdlein, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (3 copies) (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Vielleicht, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/20)
      - Volkslied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 8.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/21)
      - Volkslied, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/21)
      - Vollmondnacht, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 2.7.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/22)
      - Vollmondnacht, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/22)
      - Vor Gericht, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/23)
      - Vorschlag zur Güte, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 12.9.68 London. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/24)
      - Wandrers Gemüthsruhe, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 29.1.70 London. (Box-folder 10/25)
      - Wandrers Gemüthsruhe, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/25)
      - Wandrers Nachtlied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 7.12.67 Zürich. (Box-folder 10/26)
      - Wandrers Nachtlied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 6.6.68 Wien. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/27)
      - Was frag ich viel nach Geld und Gut see [Lieder: Der Zufriedene]
      - Was machst du an der Welt, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Zürich 7.2.67. (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Was machst du an der Welt, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Was soll ich sagen, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Buenos Aires 1951. (Box-folder 10/29)
      - Was soll werden see [Lieder] Gebet [Was soll werden]
      - Was wird mir jede Stunde so bang? [Version 1], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 24.4.67 Zürich. (Box-folder 10/30)
      - Was wird mir jede Stunde so bang? [Version 1], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/30)
      - Was wird mir jede Stunde so bang? [Version 2], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 27.4.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/31)
      - Was wird mir jede Stunde so bang? [Version 2], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 4.9.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/31)
      - Wechsellied zum Tanz, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 13.12.67 Z. (Box-folder 10/32)
      - Wechsellied zum Tanz, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/32)
      - Wenn die Rosen ewig blühten, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Wenn die Rosen ewig blühten, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Von Otto Klemperer Nov. 1908. (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Wer nie sein Brot mit Tränen ass see [Lieder] Harfenspieler [Wer nie sein Brot]
      - Wer sich der Einsamkeit ergibt see [Lieder] Harfenspieler [Wer sich der Einsamkeit]
      - Westöstlicher Divan see Sie haben wegen der Trunkenheit see [Lieder] Suleika
      - Wie ein Volkslied, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/34)
      - Wiegenlied see also [Lieder] Schlaflied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 3.1.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/35)
      - Willst du dir ein hübsch' Leben zimmern [version 1], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 23.4.68 Z. (Box-folder 10/36)
      - Willst du dir ein hübsch' Leben zimmern [version 2], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/37)
      - Wo?, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 25.7.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 10/38)
      - Woher sind wir geboren?, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/39)
      - Der Zufriedene, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 10/40)
    - [Merry-valse and one-step]
      - Merry valse, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Merry valse, Photocopy of copyist manuscript full score with emendations (3 copies) (Box-folder 103/3-4)
      - Merry valse, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 103/5)
      - Merry valse, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 103/6)
      - Merry valse, Parts, except strings
        - Copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 11/2)
        - Photocopy of copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Merry valse, Parts, strings
        - Copyist's manuscript (transparencies) (Box-folder 11/4)
        - Photocopy of copyists's manuscript (2 sets) (Box-folder 11/5-12/1)
        - Permalife photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with markings, LOAN MATERIAL (NOT TO BE LOANED). (Box-folder 103/7)
        - Permalife photocopy of parts, LOAN MATERIAL (NOT TO BE LOANED). (Box-folder 103/8)
        - Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with markings, LOAN MATERIAL (TO BE LOANED WITH PERMISSION ONLY). (Box-folder 104/1)
        - Photocopy of parts, LOAN MATERIAL (TO BE LOANED WITH PERMISSION ONLY). (Box-folder 104/2)
    - Missa Sacra, Printed piano-vocal score with markings (2 copies); On t.p.: inscription. (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Missa Sacra, Printed full score with markings [missing p. 1-2]; On t.p.: inscription. (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Missa Sacra, Photocopy of printed full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Morgenlied, Photocopy of manuscript piano score; At end: illegible inscription. (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Der Musensohn, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Der Musensohn, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Nocturne, Copyist's piano score with emendations (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Pater noster, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 13.1.69 Z. (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Pater noster, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Pater noster und Ave Maria, Printed full score; On cover: inscription. (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Pater noster und Ave Maria, Parts with emendations (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Pianopiece (Ressentiment), Copyist's manuscript piano score (transparencies) (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Pianopiece (Ressentiment), Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano score (2 copies) (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Der Prediger Salomo, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 24.8.69 Z. (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Der Prediger Salomo, Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations; Laid in: text in German and Hebrew. (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Der Prediger Salomo, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Der Prediger Salomo, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (transparencies) (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Psalms IV, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 26.8.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Psalms IV, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Psalm 23 (aus "Saul & David") see also [Lieder] Psalm 23, Holograph manuscript harp-voice score; At end: 2.10.61 Zürich. (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Psalm 23 (aus "Saul & David") see also [Lieder] Psalm 23, Copyist's manuscript harp-voice score (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Psalmus 42 (Judica me), Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 13/15)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 12.5.68 Z. (Box-folder 14/1)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2], Copyist's manuscript score (transparencies) (Box-folder 14/2)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript score with emendations (4 copies) (Box-folder 14/3)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2], Parts
      - (Transparencies) (Box-folder 14/4)
      - Photocopy with markings, (3 sets) (Box-folder 14/5-7)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 29.12.68 Z. (Box-folder 14/8)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3], Photocopy of holograph manuscript score (transparencies) (Box-folder 14/9)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3], Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 14/10)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3], Parts with markings (Box-folder 14/11)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 4], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 22.2.69 London. (Box-folder 15/1)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 4], Copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 15/2)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 4], Parts (Box-folder 15/3)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 5], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 6.4.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 15/4)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 5], Copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 15/5)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 5], Parts (Box-folder 15/6)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 6], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 22.4.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 15/7)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 6], Copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 15/8)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 6], Parts (Box-folder 15/9)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 7], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 20.10.69 London. (Box-folder 16/1)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 7], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript score (transparencies) (Box-folder 16/2)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 7], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 16/3)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 7], Parts
      - Photocopy of copyist's manuscript, Transparencies (Box-folder 16/4)
      - Photocopy of copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 16/5)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 8], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 9.8.68 Z. (Box-folder 16/6)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 8], Copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 16/7)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 8], Parts (Box-folder 16/8)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 9], Holograph manuscript score; At end: 17.12.70 Zürich. (Box-folder 16/9)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 9], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 16/10)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 9], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript score (2 copies) (Box-folder 16/11)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 9], Parts (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Recollections see also [Symphony no. 2], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 1968. On t.p.: (Urspruenglich aus 2ter version der Sinfonie No. 2). (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Recollections, Parts (Box-folder 13/17-18)
    - Reiterlied, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 17.8.68 London (Box-folder 13/19)
    - Reiterlied, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 13/19)
    - Scherzo see also [Symphony no. 2], Copyist's manuscript full score; At end: 1968. On t.p.: (Ursprunglich aus 2ter Version der Sinfonie No. 2). (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Scherzo, Parts (Box-folder 17/2-3)
    - Scherzo, Copyist's manuscript piano score (transparencies) (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Scherzo, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano score (5 copies) (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Schildwache und Freund Hein, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 2.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Schildwache und Freund Hein, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Schlaflied "Schlaf, mein Kind, schlaf ein", Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Schlaflied [Schlaf, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 27.1.68. (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Schlaflied [Schlaf, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Serenata, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 6.1.69. (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Serenata, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 17/9)
    - [Sketchbooks], 1967-1971, undated (Box-folder 37/1-4)
    - Ständchen, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 106/2)
    - Ständchen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Ständchen, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript vocal part (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Studie für Klavier, Photocopy of holograph manuscript for piano; On p. 1: For Miss [?] Epstein. (Box-folder 17/12)
    - Studie für Klavier, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript for piano (2 copies); On p. 1: For Miss [?] Epstein. (Box-folder 17/12)
    - Studie für Violine & Klavier, Copyist's manuscript violin-piano score (Box-folder 17/13)
    - [Symphony in 2 movements], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 21.9.60 Zürich. (Box-folder 18/1)
    - [Symphony in 2 movements], Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations; On front flyleaf: alterations; orchestration. (Box-folder 106/3)
    - [Symphony in 2 movements], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 18/2)
    - [Symphony in 2 movements], Printed full score (3 copies) (Box-folder 18/3)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 1] see also Recollections see also Scherzo, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 17.8.67 London. (Box-folder 18/4)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 1], Zweiter Satz [1. Fassung], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 18/5)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 1], Dritter Satz, Scherzo [1. Fassung], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 18/6)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 2], Printed full score; Laid in: typewritten possible changes in German and English. (Box-folder 18/7)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 2] 2. Satz, 2. Fassung! [?], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 9.3.68 London. Note: [version 1?]. (Box-folder 18/8)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 2] [3.] Scherzo, 2. Fassung! [?], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 30.3.68 London. (Box-folder 18/9)
    - [Symphony no. 2] [Version 2], Parts (2. Fassung) (transparencies) (Box-folder 18/10)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 1], Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 19/1)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 1], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 19/2)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 1], Parts (transparencies) (Box-folder 19/3)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 2], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 3.4.71 Zürich. (Box-folder 19/4)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 2] I. Satz, II. Satz [version 2], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 19/5)
    - [Symphony no. 3] [Version 2] III. Satz [version 2], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (3 copies) (Box-folder 19/6)
    - I. Satz, II. Satz [version 2]
      - Parts, except strings, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 20/1)
      - Parts, strings, Transparencies (Box-folder 20/3)
      - Parts, strings, photocopy of copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 20/4-5)
    - III. Satz, IV. Satz [version 2]
      - Parts, except strings, photocopy (Box-folder 20/2)
      - Parts, strings, photocopy of copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 21/1-2)
    - [Symphony no. 4], Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 21/3)
    - [Symphony no. 4], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 21/4)
    - [Symphony no. 5], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 16.11.69 Z. (Box-folder 22/1)
    - [Symphony no. 5], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 22/2)
    - [Symphony no. 6], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 17.6.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 22/3)
    - [Symphony no. 6], Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 22/4)
    - [Symphony no. 6], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Tema für [illegible] Variationen, Photocopy of holograph manuscript for piano; On p. 1: Orginal [sic] bei: M. Mihalovici, 15 rue du Dragon, Paris (6). (Box-folder 23/1)
    - [Thamar]
      - Marcia funebre (of "Thamar"), Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 26.6.60 Zürich. (Box-folder 23/2)
      - Marcia funebre aus Oper "Thamar", Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: Otto Klemperer "Marcia Funebré aus Oper "Thamar" Partitur. (Box-folder 23/3)
      - Marcia funebre aus Oper "Thamar", Photocopy of holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 23/3)
      - Marcia funebre (of "Thamar"), Copyist's manuscript parts (transparencies) (Box-folder 23/4)
      - Marcia funebre (of "Thamar"), Parts (Box-folder 23/5)
      - Thamar, Photocopy of manuscript piano-vocal score; Laid in: letter to Paul Gergely from Lotte Klemperer and receipt. (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Die überflüssige Vorsicht, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Die überflüssige Vorsicht, Photocopy of piano-vocal score (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Die überflüssige Vorsicht, Parts (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Unter Feinden, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 25.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Unter Feinden, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: Dort der Galgen, hier die Stricke. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Variationen für Klavier, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano score (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Der verlorene Sohn
      - 1.-3. Bild, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 24/1)
      - 4.-6. Bild, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 12.12.68 Z. (Box-folder 24/2)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 24/3)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 24/4)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (2 copies); On p. 1 of 1 copy: (Lukas Kap. 15, 11-32). (Box-folder 106/4)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies) (Box-folder 24/5)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Libretti (4 copies) (Box-folder 25/1)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, except strings, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 25/2)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, strings (transparencies) (Box-folder 25/3)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, strings, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 25/4)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, strings, photocopy (Box-folder 26)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, off stage chorus (transparency) (Box-folder 25/5)
      - 1.-6. Bild, Parts, chorus, photocopy (Box-folder 25/5)
    - Die vier Elemente, Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: Begonnen 3. Juni 1915 beendet 14. Juni 1915 Hamburg Abendroths Weg 33. (Box-folder 23/11)
    - Die vier Elemente, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 23/12)
    - Wehen, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 23/13)
    - Wiegenlied, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 14.1.68. (Box-folder 23/14)
    - Wiegenlied, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1933; Schlafe, mein Kindchen, schlaf ein. (Box-folder 23/14)
    - Wiegenlied, Copyist's manuscript full score; At end: Meiner Marianne zum 10. Februar 1933 mit allen guten Wünschen von ihrem Otto. (Box-folder 23/15)
    - Die Weber, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 30.12.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 27/1)
    - Die Weber, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 27/2)
    - Die Weber, Parts, except strings, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 27/3)
    - Die Weber, Parts, strings (transparencies) (Box-folder 27/4)